There is nothing like cold cereal
topped with fresh blueberries
on a hot summer morning.
- Agh.
- Finish your milk.
Morning, everybody.
Any room out here for me? - No.
I'll get that. Clyde, why
don't you take my seat?
Thanks.
Uh, look, Mr. Lewis, um,
I swear to you I had no
idea Lucy left me the house,
and if I had, I would've tried
to talk her out of it. I mean it.
But you know my feeling is if your
sister really wanted me to have it,
then I should accept it, if
only out of respect for her.
Half a million dollars you're
gonna turn around and sell it for.
That's what you respect.
Well, it just so happens,
my boy here is a lawyer,
and by the time we get
done contesting that will,
you won't get so
much as a dust buster.
Pass the jelly.
Clyde.
This is Detective Kendall from
the Wilmington Police Department.
He'd like to talk to you.
About what?
Mike Rydell was
murdered last night.
- The lifeguard?
- Yeah.
I need to know where you were
between 6:00 and 9:00 last night.
Um, I was at work till 6:30
and then I changed clothes, uh,
went on my usual run, came back
here, took a shower and ate dinner.
And then he was
here with us till 7:30.
- Where do you run?
- On the beach.
Uh, out to Figure 8 Cove
and back, same as always.
That'd take you right
past Mike Rydell's place.
Preliminary indications
are that he died sometime
between 6:00
and 9:00 last night.
I understand that you had
some sort of altercation with him
on the beach yesterday.
Yeah. He slugged me.
I also understand you're an
insulin-dependent diabetic.
What's that have
to do with anything?
Since Mr. Rydell appears
to have died from an injection
of some kind of poison,
we're particularly interested
in the syringe that
was found at the scene,
one like people who have to give
themselves shots are prescribed.
Maybe you should
just come downtown.
Clyde, we'll get things together
here and we'll meet you down there.
- Come on, Dad, let's go.
- I'm having bread and jelly.
- Come on. Let's go.
- I'm having toast and jelly.
- I'll go with you, Leanne.
- Thank you.
You help that gold-digger,
you're dog meat.
Probably did kill that guy.
Probably killed Lucy too.
Did you ever think of that?
Wait a minute.
If I could prove he did kill her, he
wouldn't get the house, would he?
I said, if I could prove he did kill her,
he wouldn't get the house, would he?
Say it.
You were thinking it.
Go ahead and say it.
Jackass.
Ugh, we didn't get along.
What happened at the beach?
I told him that he ought to spend
more time watching the water
instead of the girls
and he decked me.
- Did that embarrass you?
- Well, yeah.
So, now, I guess the DA will
say that I wanted revenge. Right?
- Probably.
- Great.
Found your fingerprints
on the syringe.
Listen, I have a special container
for used syringes in the garage.
Somebody must have stolen them.
The lab found traces of insulin
and a poison called Monocaine in it.
Monocaine. I never heard of it.
Somebody's setting
you up pretty good.
When the police
searched the surf shop,
they found a vial
of it in your desk.
Great. I don't get it.
Who knew you'd be
out running last night?
Everybody. I swim before
work and run right after.
People use me
to set their clocks.
Look. I did not
kill Mike Rydell,
although my chances of
convincing the jury of that
are getting pretty
slim, aren't they?
The state's evidence
is all circumstantial.
Nobody saw you commit the crime.
The police can't even
place you at the scene.
With any luck,
between them and us,
we'll find the real killer before
this thing gets anywhere near a jury.
- Well, there's no sign of a struggle.
- This place is so neat.
You know, it looks
like he just vacuumed.
Well, he was killed
in the bedroom.
Wonder what the killer
was doing in the bedroom.
Hey! have you ever
given anyone a shot?
Mm-mm.
Me, neither. Needles
give me the heebie jeebies.
Well, that's odd.
- What? LEANNE:
There's no clock in here.
Do you see a clock?
No. None.
Well, you gotta have a clock.
You can't get up in the
morning without a clock.
Well, unless you have a
watch that has an alarm.
True.
- Ms. Mclntyre?
- Oh, in here.
Nevil told me he'd given
you some keys to the place.
I'm glad I caught you.
I've located someone who can place
your client at the scene of the crime.
Figured you'd wanna know.
Can't you just give me a break?
Please, I'm just trying
to help out my client.
I've already answered
these questions.
Oh, just one more time. Okay?
- Okay.
- Oh, great. Thanks.
Let's see. Uh, the phone
company's records show
that Mike placed a call at
7:04 last night to 555-7057.
- That's the number here. Right?
- Right.
You two were friends.
He wanted me to go
to a movie with him.
- Last night?
- Yeah. Last night.
- Huh. Which one?
- I don't know.
Before he could
tell me, he said...
Well, I don't
remember everything.
But there was a pause
and then he said I gotta go.
Clyde's here. I'll
call you right back.
- You sure he said Clyde?
- Positive.
How do you think he knew it
was Clyde, if he was on the phone?
Well, while he was talking,
I heard a kind of commotion
in the background,
like someone had just
opened the door and walked in.
That's when he said
he'd call me back.
Did the person that
walked in say anything?
Yeah. He said something
like, "Hey, Mike."
- I wasn't paying much attention.
- Did it sound like Clyde?
I don't know. I couldn't
hear him very well.
But you're sure he
said, "Clyde's here."
I told you. Yes.
Okay. All right. Sorry.
Well, if I have any more
questions, I'll call you.
- Sure.
- Okay. Bye-bye.
Bye.
Oh.
- One of you went to E.U.?
- No.
Somebody must've
left that there.
People come and go all the time.
Our place is sort of action central.
I'll bet.
Well, take care.
Not yet, not yet.
Okay.
- A ringer.
- Huh, we'll see about that.
- Yeah. You wait. You wait. You wait.
- Ha, ha.
- Ah, it's a leaner.
- What you talking about?
- That's a ringer.
- You're blind, Ben.
It didn't clear the stake
and it's leaning up against it.
No. It's not.
Oh, look, look, look, it's
leaning against that little seashell.
It's not even
touching the stake.
I don't see any seashell.
Oh, surely you can see
that seashell right there.
- I don't see it. It's a leaner.
- It's a ringer.
- What are you all doing?
- Uh, here, your father's cheating.
I'm not cheating. I don't
need to cheat. I never cheat.
I got a ringer and
he said it's a leaner.
Dad, could I talk
to you for a second?
- It's a leaner. I win.
- It's a ringer. I win.
Dad. Let's...
No. Get down there and
tell him that's a ringer.
Excuse us, Billy.
Dad, excuse me, uh.
- Jackass is too blind to see a ringer.
- I just went to see... Listen.
I just went to see this woman
named Ashley Armstrong.
She's got a roommate
named Carrie Locke.
Now, when I first
met Tim McDaniels...
- Billy.
- Dad.
Are you with me? I'm right here.
I'd like you to listen for a second.
I just went to see a woman
named Ashley Armstrong.
She's got a roommate
named Carrie Locke.
- When I first met Tim...
- Billy.
Dad, are you with me? When
I first met Tim McDaniels,
the guy that drowned, he was
wearing an Eton University windbreaker.
When he drowned, he was
wearing E.U. swim trunks.
And just now, when I
was over at Ashley's
I saw an Eton
University sweatshirt.
Didn't belong to either
one of those girls.
- I think it was Tim's.
- Billy, stop digging.
Dad, you gotta listen to me.
So then I started thinking, maybe
those two girls, Carrie and Ashley,
are running that date rape
scam that Tim told us about.
So I went down to
the local hangout
and sure enough, the bartender says
he remembers seeing Tim McDaniels
with Carrie Locke last week.
I see you blowing sand
out from under there. Stop it.
- Trying to ruin my ringer.
- Dad, you gotta listen to me.
Listen to me right now. Dad.
A lifeguard has been murdered.
Please, Pop, everything I know
leads back to these two girls.
- I need you to go see them.
- Oh, Leanne.
Please, Dad, I was just there. If I
go back, they'll be on their guard.
This needs somebody
with charm and finesse.
- Send Cliff.
- Please, Dad.
- We gotta try to help Clyde.
- Oh.
- Please, Pop.
- Leanne, I just... Please.
All right.
- Ugh.
- Okay. I guess...
I guess anything would be better
than playing horse shoes with Billy.
It's a leaner. I win.
It's a ringer. I win.
Really, Mr. Matlock,
answering the same questions
over and over again
is getting pretty old.
I'm beginning to
regret I said anything.
Oh, I bet you are.
Getting to be, what do
you call it, a drag, heh.
- Yes.
- Yeah.
Well, nice tans, heh.
- Guess you're never too old to notice.
- No. No, no.
Uh, you here for the summer?
Well, we go to nursing
school in Roanoke.
- But, yes, we're here for the summer.
- I guess so, to get those tans.
Heh, uh... Uh, did you used
to go out with Tim McDaniels?
Once or twice.
It's not going out.
Uh, somebody said that, uh,
some girl around here
accused him of attempted rape.
Wasn't me.
He left his, uh, Eton
University sweatshirt here.
- Lots of people leave clothes here.
- Oh.
Well, what about,
uh, Mike Rydell?
- Not as far as I know.
- Oh.
Uh, that night he
didn't call you back.
How come, how come
you didn't call him back?
Because I didn't
wanna go out with him.
Oh, you weren't sweet on him?
- No. I wasn't.
- Heh.
So, so, uh, what'd you, uh, just,
uh, stay here, not go anywhere?
Yep, spent the whole
evening right here.
Huh.
If our word isn't good
enough, just ask our neighbor.
Ask your neighbor.
Heh, um, if you don't
mind, we've got to get going.
- It's supposed to rain this afternoon.
- Oh.
You wouldn't want our tans to
fade, now, would you, Mr. Matlock?
Oh, No, heh, no, no.
Of course, you with that
T-shirt, you might not get any, uh,
get it on it...
So maybe I'll take it off.
Oh, okay, you could... Heh.
Yeah, it was nice talking
to both of you and bye.
- Hi.
Missed a spot.
- Yeah, thank you.
- Yeah.
- You one of Carrie's relatives?
- Uh, no. I'm a lawyer.
Oh! What's a girl her
age need a lawyer for?
Or shouldn't I ask?
Well, actually, uh,
you shouldn't ask, heh.
Do you know if she and
Ashley were home, uh,
day before yesterday
about, say, 6:00?
Um, yesterday.
Tuesday around 6:00.
Yeah, because that was the day
that Ashley borrowed
a cup of sugar from me.
They were making a cake.
- And you saw them?
- Mm-hm.
- Both of them?
- Uh, no. Just Ashley.
But Carrie, now, she was home
because she answered the phone
while Ashley was over here.
- So they were home all night.
- I guess.
- Heh, there now. What do you think?
- Oh, shines like a silver dollar.
A Ferrari? Why do I
have to rent Cliff a Ferrari?
Shh, you're gonna wake up Billy.
A Ferrari is part of the cover.
We wanna try to get these girls
to run their date rape scam on Cliff.
On Cliff?
See, uh, he doesn't think
it's a good idea, either.
Leanne, I am just not
good at picking up girls.
Oh, but you don't have to be.
The idea is for them to pick you up.
See, I'm dead if my father finds
out that I'm helping you help Clyde.
He's not gonna find out.
Why a Ferrari?
To make him look rich, Dad.
Give him some money.
- Oh, come on.
- Shh.
Oh, well.
I can't do it. I can't do it.
Cliff, Dad has
already rented the car.
It's embarrassing.
I'm embarrassed.
I've just never gone out
and picked up a girl before.
Well, you've never
had a Ferrari before.
That's all it takes?
Well, you're gonna
have to talk to them.
What if someone's
sitting with them?
Sit somewhere else. Look sexy.
- What if they're alone?
- Join them.
- Join them?
- Yes. Join them.
- I don't know. I...
- All right. All right. All right.
You be Carrie. I'll be you.
You see them sitting on the
beach. You walk over to them.
You say, "Hello.
Anyone sitting here?"
Okay.
- You sit.
- I sit.
You sit. You introduce
yourself. You make small talk.
- Small talk.
- Yes. Small talk.
Tell them you're new in
town. Ask them where people...
Tell them you wanna
go home with them.
Oh, maybe this
isn't a good idea.
Well, now, hold on a second.
Now, just wait a second.
Let me just... Let
me just try it on.
All right.
Okay. All right. I think
I'm gonna be all right.
- Uh, you ever driven a Ferrari?
- No.
They're stick, aren't they?
Well, well, what have we here?
Forget about it, Carrie.
Nice car.
No more. Not with all
those lawyers nosing around.
No. You're right. Absolutely.
Although he does
look like kind of a geek.
- They do make the easiest marks.
- Carrie.
Okay. Okay.
Anybody sitting here?
What's it look like?
Just wanted to make sure you
weren't saving it for somebody.
My name's Cliff Lewis.
I'm new in town, heh.
Heard this beach was
a, uh, happening place.
My banker told me that this is
where everything was happening.
Um, it happened here.
Uh, he told me that when I went to
withdraw money from my trust fund,
so that I could buy,
uh, a new polo pony.
Hey, Carrie, how's it going?
- Hi, there.
- Haven't heard from you.
- Sorry. I've been busy.
Hear what happened to that guy
that was spying on you the other night?
Yeah. Pretty weird, huh?
Man, I'll say.
Drowning like that.
- I couldn't believe it.
- Yeah, me neither.
At least he won't be
harassing you anymore.
If you ever get
unbusy, give me a call.
- Still at Beachside.
- Will do.
- Mr. Matlock.
- Hi.
You here to check
our tans again?
- No.
- Oh, Carrie and I were just leaving.
Oh, I'm supposed to tell
you be sure and call Jerry.
Jerry? MATLOCK: Jennings.
Remember, that young man
that you were entertaining
the night that, uh, Jim
McDaniels came spying on you.
Uh, Jerry and I
had a nice long talk.
And, uh, he told
me that Tim told him
that the two of you
were setting him up.
Heh, we didn't set him up.
He tried to assault me.
Not what you said before.
Look, the guy's dead.
I didn't see what good
dragging his name through
the mud was gonna do.
It's over. I just wanted to
pretend it never happened. Okay?
Sure. Sure.
Oh, uh, Mike Rydell, you say
he wanted to take you to a movie.
That's right.
Well, Leanne, you know,
my daughter, she's about...
Well, she told me that he had
broken his glasses the day before that.
So, I called some eye doctors
and sure enough he had ordered,
uh, a pair special and prescription.
So all he had was
a pair of sunglasses,
and I wondered why he
wanted to take you to a movie
that night with, uh, sunglasses
where he could barely see.
Well, maybe he didn't
really wanna see a movie.
Maybe what he was
really after was me.
Oh, well, I can... Heh.
I can certainly see that.
So excuse me. Nice... Thanks.
You don't find it odd that
the girl who can place Clyde
at the scene of the crime
rooms with the girl who
accused Tim McDaniels of rape?
What has one thing
got to do with the other?
Oh, nothing, unless Mike Rydell
intentionally drowned Tim McDaniels.
Is that what you think?
Do you know something I don't?
I think I may know what happened.
The girls wanted Tim out of the way.
Mike did it for them
and then they killed him.
Does word "proof" ring any
bells with you, Ms. Mclntyre?
Ugh.
Why don't you bring in the girls,
you question them separately.
- They're bound to slip up.
- I have no reason to do that.
The DA's happy. I'm happy.
Look here, uh, look here.
- Here.
- Oh, yeah, oh, yeah.
You didn't find any
prints on the telephone.
I didn't find any
fingerprints anywhere.
Yeah, but this Mike
called Ashley. She said.
Now, I don't know about you.
But I don't usually wipe off my
telephone after I call somebody.
Of course, if I didn't want
somebody to find my fingerprints on it,
I guess I might.
I'm Detective Kendall.
This is Detective Holt.
I don't understand. We've already
told you everything we know.
Oh, this shouldn't take too long.
Are your lawyers on their way?
We don't need lawyers.
We haven't done anything.
Well, we may as
well get started then.
Um, Ms. Locke, why
don't you have a seat?
No, no, you'll be going across
the hall with Detective Holt.
I wanna ask you some questions
about the night Mike Rydell died.
Where were you that night?
At home.
What'd you do?
Had dinner and watched a movie.
What'd you eat?
Barbecued chicken.
Thighs, which I love.
Any vegetables?
Yeah. Mashed potatoes
and a tossed salad.
And we had ice cream
and marble cake for dessert.
Anything else
you'd like to know?
- Who made the chicken?
- Carrie always cooks.
- Anyone call?
- Just Mike.
- What time?
- It was while we were eating.
Must have been around 7:00.
Who called when Ashley was
over at your neighbor's house?
Oh, that was a wrong number.
Never can find
anything in our house.
I don't know why I
can't find anything here.
Never put anything in
the same place twice.
Kitchen.
Might as well be
in the garage then.
I'm leaving.
Yeah. I suppose you're going
out to help that gigolo again.
Pop, it's my job.
- Are you gonna be all right here?
- Yeah. Yeah.
As soon as I can
find an egg poacher.
The old bat must have had
one around here somewhere.
- I'll see you later, Mr. Grumpy.
- Yeah. Yeah.
You kept a basket I made
for you at the Boy Scouts.
Only nice thing I
ever did for you.
Probably why you kept it.
I was a lousy brother. Wasn't I?
Never let you play with my toys.
Never stuck up for you
in front of the other kids.
Let you take the blame
for all the lousy things I did.
Oh, man.
Remem...? Remember
the time you got in trouble
for breaking the crank
on the washing machine?
Well, uh, that was me, Lucy.
I was pretending the Nazis
were storming the basement
and the washing
machine was a Gatling gun.
Handle broke right off.
I... Ugh.
I left it, sort of,
hanging there,
so that it looked like it was you
when you were doing the wash.
Sorry about the
whupping you got.
I'm sorry about everything.
I...
I just hope you can
hear me and you can
find it in your
heart to forgive me.
Because deep down
I never said it.
But I loved you, Lucy.
Why the hell'd you have to
leave the house to that jackass?
You let them go?
I had to. Their stories are the
same. You've seen that for yourself.
Yeah. They're exactly the same.
Right down to the same adjective.
They both say they had
barbecued chicken thighs
and a tossed salad.
It's like they rehearsed it.
- I don't think so, Ms. Mclntrye.
- Oh, Detective Kendall, please.
Leanne, Detective Kendall's
been very cooperative.
- He's done all he can. Let's go.
- No. He hasn't.
- Come on.
- Dad.
Dad. Dad, these girls are
in this up to their eyeballs.
I am more convinced of
that now than ever before.
- They probably are.
- I know.
I don't have anything on them.
- Hmm.
But I will.
Okay.
You know what today
really taught me?
To hell with nursing school.
I am going to be
an actress, heh.
Uh-oh. Bozo
approaching, 12 o'clock.
- Uh, I don't want to dump on anybody.
- Ha, ha.
- Let's be nice.
- We're not out of the woods yet.
I know. I mean, nice nice.
You do remember how
to be nice nice, don't you?
Vaguely.
Hi, heh.
Um, so we meet again, heh.
I sat next to you on
the beach the other day.
You probably don't remember.
Oh, of course we do. I
never forget a Ferrari.
I mean, a face.
- Here, sit down.
- Oh, thank you, heh.
We'd offer you a drink. But
- we're all out.
- Ha-ha-ha!
Uh, I'll take care of that.
So, um, heh, what
are we celebrating?
Oh, Carrie's just decided what
she's gonna be when she grows up.
- Oh, yeah? And that is?
- A sex therapist. Ha, ha.
Waitress... Um...
May we have one more pitcher
and an extra glass please?
I'll be glad to serve you, sir,
but I'm afraid the bartender
thinks the ladies have had enough.
What? What kind of deal is that?
Actually, it's the law.
If you got in an accident on the way
home, he could be held responsible.
I know that, uh, because, um,
because I get cut off all the time, heh.
Come on, Carrie, I think we
should take our business elsewhere.
- Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
- Ha-ha-ha.
I think that you'd
better call it a night.
I think we'd better call a cab, heh.
- Heh.
I have an idea. Why
don't you I drive you home?
Oh, well, heh.
Hey. This is a nice
place. Are you renting it?
Whoa, oh, I'm sorry.
No. It's my aunt's. She's
in Europe for the summer.
Oh. Does, uh, she have
any idea how messy you are.
- Oh, it's all Ashley's stuff.
- Very funny.
- Hey, would you get me a beer.
- Oh, me too.
Oh, I think you two
have had enough.
I'll make you some coffee.
My name's Cliff.
- Heh. Ha-ha-ha.
- It's Bozo.
I've never seen anyone drive
a Ferrari so slow in my life.
- Ha-ha-ha.
- What do you want in your coffee?
Cream and sugar. - Kahlua.
Hey, you know what?
Your sugar is as hard as a rock.
Oh, humidity gets to it
after a while. It's still good.
I gotta go. I just remembered.
There's some place that I gotta be.
- I'm really sorry.
- It's almost midnight.
Yeah. Oh, yeah, that's... Whoa,
wow. That's why I gotta hurry.
Um, I'll catch you on
the beach at some point.
There's a volleyball
tournament tomorrow.
Yeah. At 1:00. Heh,
you wanna play?
No, uh, no. I'll just watch.
I'll watch. Thanks. See you.
Bozo.
Hello? CLIFF Ben, it's Cliff.
I know it's late. But I just
discovered something.
There is sugar in
Carrie Locke's house.
Ben?
Ben, do you hear me?
Ben, wake up. MATLOCK: What?
There is sugar in Carrie's
house, almost a full 5-pound bag.
It looks like it's
been there for weeks.
Sugar.
Did you say sugar?
Yes, Ben, I said sugar,
enough to bake 12 marble cakes.
I don't know how they do it.
If they were as drunk
last night as Cliff said.
- Yeah.
Whoo!
- I wonder why that one... Carrie?
- Yeah.
I wonder why she's
wearing that T-shirt.
You'd think she'd
want to show off her tan.
They make a nice
team, don't they?
Volleyball, extortion, murder.
- Of course, I know, we need the proof.
- Yeah.
But the sugar that Cliff found proves
that Ashley didn't need to borrow
any that day from her neighbor.
She was just setting
up, uh, an alibi for Carrie.
We could suggest that.
We?
Did you say we? I
heard you say we, Dad.
Does that mean you wanna
be my co-counsel at the trial?
No more "I'm on vacation"?
Oh, Dad!
Oh, Dad.
Yes, yes, yes.
All right, two more points.
You sure you don't
wanna take this?
Oh, why don't you take it? Maybe
afterwards we can go on vacation.
Hmm.
The address you just gave
is, uh, actually your
aunt's address, isn't it?
That's right. She's in Europe
and we're house sitting.
- We?
- Ashley Armstrong and I.
She's a friend of mine from school.
- Nursing school.
Yes.
Are you, uh, are you working
here or just, uh, playing?
No. Just playing.
These are records from
the place where you bank
here in Wilmington, Ms. Locke.
And, uh, during June and July,
how many deposits did you make?
- Three.
- How much money?
- Five thousand dollars.
You just said you're not working.
Where did you get that kind of money?
- It was a gift.
- Oh.
- You don't wanna say, uh...?
- No. It's personal.
- I'd rather not say.
- Oh, okay, okay.
But, uh, but was it from, uh, was it
from, uh, Jerry Jennings back there?
No.
Well, you do know
Mr. Jennings, don't you?
I went out with him once.
What happened when
you went out with him?
Or that is, when you
took him to your house?
Well, he's prepared to testify
that Tim McDaniels
showed up at your place
while Jerry was there,
claiming that you and your
roommate were trying to set Jerry up
the same way you
had set him up. Tim.
Wonder what that means.
I have no idea.
Oh, don't be modest. As
cons go, it was brilliant.
You were gonna
let him go just so far.
And then you were
gonna cry rape.
You know. Date rape.
Forcing Jerry to decide
whether to pay you off
or face the humiliation
of being arrested.
No. LAWYER: Objection.
- Excuse me. MATLOCK:
Trying to extort money
from Jerry the same way
you extorted money from Tim.
- No.
- I object!
That's where the money in
your bank account came from.
- Isn't it?
- No.
- Objection.
- Mr. Matlock.
Yes, sir?
- Knock it off.
- Knock what off?
Making unfounded accusations, trying
to pass wild speculation off as fact.
- Your Honor...
- If I have to use
my gavel again, Mr. Matlock,
you're going to regret it.
- Is that clear?
- Yes, sir.
Now, regardless of the veracity,
the truth of Mr. McDaniels'
allegations that night,
he did indicate that he was going to
hassle you for the rest of the summer.
- Didn't he?
- Yes.
- You didn't like that?
- Heh, of course not.
Would you please tell the court
what happened to
Mr. McDaniels the very next day?
He drowned.
And who was the lifeguard who
swam out and tried to save him?
Mike Rydell.
- The decedent.
- Yes.
A very interesting coincidence.
- Did you know Mike Rydell?
- Yes.
So well, that you asked him
to get rid of Tim McDaniels
for you, didn't you?
No. LAWYER: Objection.
So he did. But then
he became the problem
and you had to get
rid of him, didn't you?
- No.
- Objection.
When you saw him slug my client
on the beach the very next day,
knowing he was diabetic, you
saw a way to go through with it?
- It's not true.
- Your Honor.
So you went to Clyde Eller's
house, stole one of his used syringes,
used a rag or
gloves or something
- to keep your fingerprints off of it.
- That's not true.
Filled it with
Monocaine, - Excuse me.
Went back to Mike Rydell's
place and injected him. Didn't you?
- No.
- Excuse me.
And then, after he died, you
picked up the phone again,
didn't leave fingerprints,
and called Ashley,
so she could implicate Clyde
Eller when the police questioned her.
Don't!
- You wanna say that again?
- Uh.
Please, Your Honor, don't.
I have proof.
- You have proof?
- Yes, sir.
Proof that Ms. Locke was in the
decedent's apartment that day.
- Let's see it, Mr. Matlock.
- Right here, right here.
Here, Your Honor. Right here.
Now, uh, you play volleyball.
Tell the court what this is.
It's a trophy they gave out at the
volleyball championships last year.
I borrowed this from,
uh, one of the winners.
It's, uh, it's pretty neat.
It's a clock and a
trophy all rolled into one.
See that? It's nice, heh.
- Did Mike Rydell have one of these?
- How should I know?
He won a championship
match with Kip Vogel last year.
So, yes, he had one.
The thing is,
nobody could find it.
Not in his apartment.
Not in his car.
But the weird thing is, the
lady who cleans his place
said she saw one exactly like
this on the nightstand by his bed
that afternoon, just hours
before he was murdered.
What happened to it, Carrie?
How should I know?
Mike struggled with you
before he died. Didn't he?
I was nowhere near his place.
- Excuse me. MATLOCK:
He grabbed that trophy
and swung it at you. - No.
- Excuse me. MATLOCK:
And he caught you
on the arm, made two deep cuts
here, so deep they keep opening up,
and they mark you, they
mark you as a murderer.
Excuse me. CARRIE: No.
- But...
- Excuse me.
Mr. Matlock,
can't you hear me
saying "Excuse me"?
Yes, sir.
That doesn't mean I
want to leave the room.
- I know, sir.
- I gave you fair warning.
Your Honor, make
her roll up her sleeve.
Please. Her left sleeve.
If there's nothing there,
you can bang your gavel
and I'll go straight to the pokey
without a word, cross my heart.
I can't pass up a deal like that.
Push up your left sleeve, please.
Push it up or I will hold
you in contempt, young lady.
I wanna talk to a lawyer.
You're a very
pretty girl, Carrie.
So is Ashley.
But somewhere back
there, you made a wrong turn.
But I think we all know
what happened to Mike Rydell
and how it happened and what
happened to Tim McDaniels.
And I think we all know that
Clyde Eller had nothing to do with it.
You're a very patient man,
Your Honor. Thank you.
- Oh, I'll get it.
- Oh, good, good.
Come on, Pop.
Clyde helped me make
sandwiches for the road.
Oh, please, it was
the least I could do.
You're going running awfully
early this morning, aren't you?
- Well.
- You can run but you can't hide.
You haven't heard
the last from me, pal.
I'm going straight
to my real lawyer.
- You didn't tell him?
- No.
- Tell me what?
- Clyde signed the house over to me
yesterday in lieu of my fee.
- You own this house?
- Well, yeah.
It's not fair.
You left her, broke her heart,
I had to take care of her
year after year after year
and she left me, took
half of everything I had
and you, one of the richest
men in the world and here's me,
a penniless jackass and
you end up with her house.
I signed it over to
you this morning.
Ooh.
- I see you told him about the house.
- Yeah.
Congratulations, Pop.
Did you, uh, tell him
about the mortgage?
- No.
- What mortgage?
Well, the $4000 mortgage
payments you'll have to make.
- Four thousand?
- Every month.
How about the
problem with the roof?
- What problem with the roof?
- It leaks. All over.
It has to be replaced.
I'd do the wiring first, though.
- What's wrong with the wiring?
- It was done on the cheap.
The whole place
could go up in flames.
But now that it's all over
and you have the house,
I'm sure that's the way
Lucy would have wanted it.
And remember our...
Our horseshoe game?
Mine was a leaner. You won.
www.tvsubtitles.net